# Oisin Tohak

## Junior Fullstack Developer

HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT, REACT, PYTHON

Portfolio: www.oisintohak.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oisintohak/

Github: https://github.com/oisintohak

Email: mail@oisintohak.com

I'm an accomplished Fullstack developer with extended experience in education and hospitality. Equally comfortable working independently and within a sprint-based agile team environment. A skilled problem-solver and constant learner, I pride myself on delivering a first-rate user experience with every project.

<u>SKILLS</u>		
<u>Frontend</u>	Backend	<u>Transferable</u>
HTML 5	Python	Problem Solving
CSS 3	Flask	Adaptability
JavaScript	Django	Communication
React	PostgreSQL	Creativity

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Atomic, Remote** -Web Developer Internship (React.js)

JULY 2021 - PRESENT

Atomic.dev is building a low-code platform that will drastically reduce development time. I'm involved in developing the frontend of this platform. My duties include:

- Maintain clear and consistent communication with team members to ensure code consistency.
- Translating Figma designs into high quality code.
- Develop user-facing features using React, Redux and styled-components.
- Sending requests to the platform API and handling response data.
- Develop components to handle and process user input.

#### Govindas, Galway Ireland - Catering

2012 - 2014, 2015 - 2021

I was involved in all aspects of running a successful catering business. I was the sole operator of this business for extended periods. Duties included:

- Preparing a selection of Indian vegetarian dishes to serve upwards of 400 customers per day.
- Training new staff to correctly follow the correct procedure and ensure that team members operate efficiently with each other.
- Adhering to health and safety requirements, recording consistent temperature checks and sanitation.

#### Freelance/Self-employed - Drum Teacher

2016 - PRESENT

I have been playing drums since 2005 and began giving lessons from my home studio in 2016.

- •
- Inspiring people to commit to a scheduled regular donation.

Representing the business and ensuring that all encounters with the public left a positive impression.

#### Oxfam, Dublin Ireland - Fundraiser

2014

I worked with a team as a direct dialogue, door-to-door fundraiser. My duties included:

- Informing people about our various campaigns and humanitarian efforts.
- Inspiring people to commit to a scheduled regular donation.
- Ensuring that all encounters with the public left a positive impression.

### **EDUCATION**

#### Code Institute (Ireland/Remote) - Diploma in Software Development

SEPT 2020 - AUG 2021

This was a fully remote course and it is the only University Credit-Rated bootcamp in Europe. Being on a remote course gave me the skillset to communicate and collaborate effectively within a distributed team and I have participated in 2 student hackathons during this course. It is divided into 4 modules and corresponding projects:

- User Centric Frontend Development:
  - o HTML5 & CSS3
  - Mobile-first and responsive design.
  - Project Planning and developing from user stories.
  - User Experience
- Interactive Frontend Development
  - Javascript (ES6 & jQuery)
  - Interacting with APIs
  - o Responding to user input
- Data Centric Development
  - Python
  - Flask Framework
  - $\circ$  SQL
  - MongoDB
- Full Stack Frameworks
  - o Django Framework
  - o PostgreSQL
  - Ecommerce Development & Payment Processing

## **HOBBIES & INTERESTS**

- As I like to keep up to date with emerging technologies and trends in the industry I read a lot of tech-related articles on sites like Medium and Wired. I also subscribe to development related podcasts such as Syntax.fm and CodeNewbie.
- I've been playing drums and percussion for as long as I can remember and I seize any opportunity to play with other musicians in styles ranging from Metal to Funk to Indian classical music.